Mohammad Sulayman Rezaie

Glen Allen, VA 23060 | (804) 350-1722 | msulaymanr@outlook.com | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>GitHub</u> Fully Work Authorized · No Visa Sponsorship Required

SUMMARY

Software Engineering student with more than 1 year of experience in developing web, android and PC applications, using Python, Java, SQL, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. I Have an immense passion for learning programming and expanding my knowledge in coding.

Languages and Tools worked with:

Back-end: Python, Django, Java, C++, Bash, PHP Database Design: SQL,

Front-end: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap SQLite

PROJECTS

<u>CryptoDen</u> 05/2021

 Used Python with PySide and PyQt libraries to develop desktop application that performs text-based encryption and decryption using variety of symmetric ciphers, categorized into Substitution, Transposition, Combination, Stream, Block

Home Services Android Application

12/2020

 Developed Android application using Java and SQLite in Android Studio to allow users to find and request domestic services from clients that have registered and are providing expertise

AYAT Clothing Website 04/2020

 Developed clothing/fashion semi-dynamic website using HTML, CSS, PHP, and JavaScript for a startup clothing company, increasing business sales by 60% after development of website

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Intern

06/2021 - 08/2021

E-Spot Educational & Entrepreneurial Organization

Kabul, Afghanistan

- Designed and developed cashless payment system with database, reducing need for transactions through paper money for small businesses and clients and improving efficiency and efficacy of business transactions
- Developed system using Python, with PyQt and PySide libraries to design graphical user interface, and MySQL to design system's database
- Introduced improved efficiency and efficacy in various business transactions through usage of rechargeable RFID cards, allowing users to become familiar with credit card payment processes and reduce need for paper cash

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Volunteer Help Desk Support Technician

10/2021 - 11/2021

Fort Dix Army Base

Burlington County, New Jersey, USA

- Prepared and managed an online reservation system for laptop PCs to be used by guests
- Configured, managed and troubleshot 50+ laptop PCs running various operating systems such as Windows, Ubuntu, and Chrome OS

IT Teaching Assistant American University of Afghanistan

10/2020 - 05/2021

Kabul, Afghanistan

- Assisted 50+ undergraduate students in computer science courses by guiding in installation and configuration of various programming development environments, such as MySQL Server, RStudio, Jupyter Notebook, and MatLab
- Organized events for IT students through planning, scheduling, poster design, and document drafts

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology (B.Sc. IT), Software Engineering American University of Afghanistan

Kabul, Afghanistan

02/2018

Expected graduation date May 2023

Honors & Awards: President's Honor Award, Spring 2020